<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="webservice_gui">
    <title>Webszolgáltatás grafikus felülete</title>
    <para>
        A webszolgáltatások grafikus felhasználói felülete (GUI) egy olyan eszköz,
amely egy felhasználóbarát és kényelmes felületen teszi lehetővé összetett
webszolgáltatás beállítások felépítését. Lehetővé teszi:
    </para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Webszolgáltatások létrehozását és törlését.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Beállítások importálását és exportálását (YAML fájlformátumban) meglévő
webszolgáltatásokhoz.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Régi beállítások megtekintését, visszaállítását és exportálását a meglévő
webszolgáltatásokhoz a webszolgáltatás előzmények képernyőn.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Az összes kommunikációs napló követését minden webszolgáltatásnál a
hibakereső képernyőn.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <section id="webservice_gui_overview">
        <title>Webszolgáltatás áttekintés</title>
        <para>
            The <emphasis>Web Services</emphasis> link in the main screen of Admin
Interface (in the System Administration box) leads to the web services
overview screen, where you are able to manage your web service
configurations. You can add new web services or change the configuration of
the existing ones from this screen.
        </para>
        <para>
            Every web service configuration screen has in the upper part of the screen a
<emphasis>bread crumbs</emphasis> style navigation path. This navigation
path is useful to know exactly in which part of the web service
configuration we are, and also enables the user to jump back to any part of
the configuration process at any time (this action will not save any
changes).
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                To create a new web service, press the button <emphasis>Add web
service</emphasis>, and provide the required information.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Webszolgáltatások áttekintő</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-overview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_add">
        <title>Webszolgáltatás hozzáadása</title>
        <para>
            The only required field in this part is the web service
<emphasis>Name</emphasis> that needs to be unique in the system and can not
be left empty. Other fields are also necessary for the configuration like
the <emphasis>Debug Threshold</emphasis> and <emphasis>Validity</emphasis>
but these fields are already populated with the default value for each list.
        </para>
        <para>
            The default value for <emphasis>Debug Threshold</emphasis> is
<emphasis>debug</emphasis>. When configured in this manner all communication
logs are registered in the database. Each subsequent <emphasis>Debug
Threshold</emphasis> value is more restrictive and discards communication
logs of lower order than the one set in the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <title>A hibakeresési küszöbszint szintjei (az alacsonyabbtól a magasabbig)</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Hibakeresés
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Információ
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Értesítés
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Hiba
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>
            It is also possible to define the network transport protocol for
<emphasis>OTRS as Provider</emphasis> and <emphasis>OTRS as
requester</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para>
            Click on the <emphasis>Save</emphasis> button to register the new web
service in the database or click <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to discard this
operation. You will now be returned to the web service overview screen.
        </para>
        <para>
            If you already have a web service configuration file in YAML format you can
click on the <emphasis>Import web service</emphasis> button on the left side
of the screen. For more information on importing web services please check
the next section <emphasis>Web Service Change</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Egy webszolgáltatás megváltoztatásához vagy további részletek hozzáadásához
kattintson a webszolgáltatás nevére a webszolgáltatás áttekintő képernyőjén.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Webszolgáltatások hozzáadása</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-add.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_examples">
        <title>Webszolgáltatás példa importálása</title>
        <para>
            Tudta, hogy léteznek elérhető példa webszolgáltatások az <ulink
url="http://otrs.github.io/doc/manual/otrs-business-solution/stable/hu/html/import-example-web-service.html">OTRS
Business Solution™</ulink> csomagban?
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_change">
        <title>Webszolgáltatás megváltoztatása</title>
        <para>
            Ezen a képernyőn függvények teljes készlete van egy webszolgáltatás minden
részének kezeléséhez. A bal oldalon a művelet oszlopban néhány gombot
találhat, amelyek lehetővé teszik az összes lehetséges művelet végrehajtását
egy webszolgáltatáson:
        </para>
        <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Webszolgáltatás klónozása.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Webszolgáltatás exportálása.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Webszolgáltatás importálása.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Beállítási előzmények.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Webszolgáltatás törlése.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Hibakereső.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Configuration history</emphasis> and <emphasis>Debugger</emphasis>
will lead you to different screens.
            </para>
        </note>

        <section id="webservice-clone">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás klónozása</title>
            <para>
                To clone a web service, you need to click on the <emphasis>Clone web
service</emphasis> button. A dialog will be shown where you can use the
default name or set a new name for the (cloned) web service.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Remember</emphasis> that the name of the web service must be
unique within the system.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>Click on <emphasis>Clone</emphasis> button to create the web service clone
or <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the dialog.</para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatás klónozása</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-clone.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-export">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás exportálása</title>
            <para>
                The <emphasis>Export web service</emphasis> button gives you the opportunity
to dump the configuration of the current web service into a YAML file, to
download it and to store it on your file system. This can be specially
useful if you want to migrate the web service from one server to another,
for example from a testing environment to a production system.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    A webszolgáltatás beállításaiban tárolt összes jelszó egyszerű szöveges
formátumban lesz exportálva.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <para>
                Right after clicking the <emphasis>Export web service</emphasis> button a
save dialog of your browser will appear, just like when you click on a file
download link on a web page.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Az egyes operációs rendszereken minden böngészőnek saját mentési
párbeszédablak képernyője és stílusa van. A böngészőtől és annak
beállításától függően lehetséges, hogy nem jelenik meg párbeszédablak, és a
fájl az alapértelmezett könyvtárba lesz elmentve a fájlrendszeren. Nézze meg
a böngészője dokumentációját a konkrétabb utasításokért, ha szükséges.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatások exportálása</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-export.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-import">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás importálása</title>
            <para>
                A valid web service configuration YAML file is required to use the import
web service feature. Click on the <emphasis>Import web service</emphasis>
button, browse for the configuration file or provide the complete path in
the input box.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click <emphasis>Import</emphasis> button to create a new web service from a
file or "Cancel" to close the dialog.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The web service name will be taken from the configuration file name (e.g. if
the file name is <filename>MyWebservice.yml</filename> the resulting web
service will be named <emphasis>MyWebservice</emphasis>). If a web service
is registered in the system with the same name as the web service that you
want to import, the system will lead you to the web service change screen to
let you change the name of the imported web service.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatások importálása</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-import.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-history">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás előzmények</title>
            <para>
                Every change to the web service configuration creates a new entry in the web
service history (as a journal). The web service history screen displays a
list of all configuration versions for a web service. Each row (version) in
the <emphasis>Configuration History List</emphasis> represents a single
revision in the web service history.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click on one of the rows to show the whole configuration as it was on that
particular date / time. The configuration will be shown in the
<emphasis>History details</emphasis> section of this screen. Here you are
also able to export the selected web service configuration version or to
restore that version into the current web service configuration.
            </para>
            <para>
                The <emphasis>Export web service configuration</emphasis> behaves exactly as
the "Export web service" feature in the web service change screen. For more
information refer to that section.
            </para>
            <para>
                If changes to the current web service configuration do not work as expected
and it is not easy to revert the changes manually, you can click on the
<emphasis>Revert web service configuration</emphasis> button. This will open
a dialog to ask you if you are sure to revert the web service
configuration. Click <emphasis>Revert web service configuration</emphasis>
in this dialog to replace the current configuration with the selected
version, or click <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the dialog.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    Ne feledje, hogy a webszolgáltatás beállításaiban tárolt összes jelszó
egyszerű szöveges formátumban lesz exportálva.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Legyen óvatos egy beállítás visszaállításakor, mert ez a folyamat
visszafordíthatatlan.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatás előzmények</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-history.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-delete">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás törlése</title>
            <para>
                Sometimes it is necessary to delete a web service completely.  To do this
you can press on the <emphasis>Delete web service</emphasis> button and a
new dialog will appear asking for confirmation.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click on <emphasis>Delete</emphasis> to confirm the removal of the web
service or on <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the dialog.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    Egy webszolgáltatás törlése nem vonható vissza, ezért legyen óvatos egy
webszolgáltatás törlésekor.
                </para>
             </warning>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatás törlése</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-delete.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-debugger">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás hibakereső</title>
            <para>
                A hibakereső tárolja egy webszolgáltatás naplóját. A hibakereső ablakban
nyomon követheti az összes webszolgáltatás kommunikációt, mind a
szolgáltató, mind a kérelmező típusokat.
            </para>
            <para>
                Amikor ez a képernyő megjelenik, akkor a kéréslista elkezd betölteni. Miután
a lista teljesen ki van töltve, akkor kiválaszthatja a sorok egyikét (amely
egy kommunikációs sorozatot jelent) annak részleteinek ellenőrzéséhez. Ezek
a részletek fognak megjelenni egy lenti dobozban.
            </para>
            <para>
                A képernyő jobb oldalán lévő szűrő használatával szűkítheti a kommunikációs
listát. A következőkre szűrhet:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Kommunikáció típusa (szolgáltató vagy kérelmező)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Dátum: egy bizonyos dátum előtt és/vagy után
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        A távoli IP-cím
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Ezek bármilyen kombinációja
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
                After filter settings are set, push the <emphasis>Refresh</emphasis> button
and a new list will be displayed meeting your search criteria.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    A szűrőknél a keresési feltételektől függően az új lista eredmények nélkül
is visszatérhet.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                On the left part of the screen under the action column you can select
<emphasis>Go back to the web service</emphasis> or clear the debugger log by
pushing the <emphasis>Clear</emphasis> button.  This will open a dialog that
ask you to confirm erasing of the log. Click <emphasis>Clear</emphasis> in
the dialog button to perform the action or click on
<emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close this dialog.
            </para>
            <para>
                In the <emphasis>Request details</emphasis> section you can see all the
details for the selected communication. Here you can track the complete flow
and check for possible errors or confirm success responses.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatás hibakereső</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-debugger.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-configuration-change">
            <title>Webszolgáltatás-beállítás megváltoztatása</title>
            <para>
                Returning to the web service change screen, now we are going to review the
right side of it. Here we have the possibility to modify all the general
data for a web service such as name, description, debug threshold, etc. Also
there are two more sections below that allows us to modify specific
parameters for communication types <emphasis>OTRS as Provider</emphasis> and
<emphasis>OTRS as Requester</emphasis>.
            </para>
            <para>
                A webszolgáltatás beállítását el kell menteni minden egyes szinten. Ez azt
jelenti, hogy ha egy beállítás megváltozik, akkor az egyéb, a beállítás
mélyebb részeire mutató hivatkozások le lesznek tiltva arra kényszerítve
Önt, hogy elmentse a jelenlegi beállítási szintet. A mentés után a letiltott
hivatkozások ismét újra engedélyezve lesznek, lehetővé téve a beállítás
folytatását.
            </para>
            <para>
                On the <emphasis>OTRS as provider</emphasis> section it is possible to set
or configure the network transport protocol. Only network transport
back-ends that are registered are shown on the list. To configure the
network transport click on the <emphasis>Configure</emphasis> button.  It is
also possible to add new operations in this box. To do this select one of
the available operations from the <emphasis>Add Operation</emphasis>
list. This will lead you to the operation configuration screen. After saving
the new operation it will be listed in the table above.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>OTRS as requester</emphasis> is very similar to the previous one,
but instead of <emphasis>operations</emphasis> you can add invokers here.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click the <emphasis>Save</emphasis> button to save and continue configuring
the web service, <emphasis>Save and finish</emphasis> to save and return to
the web service overview screen, or <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to discard
current configuration level changes and return to web service overview
screen.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Webszolgáltatások megváltoztatása</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-change.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Like the other Generic Interface configuration screens such as Network
Transport, Operation, Invoker and Mapping, the initial configuration (add)
screen will only present two options: <emphasis>Save</emphasis> and
<emphasis>Cancel</emphasis>. If the configuration is re-visited, a new
option <emphasis>Save and Finish</emphasis> will appear.  The behavior of
this feature is defined below.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Save</emphasis> will store the current configuration level in the
database and it will return to the previous screen to review your changes or
to configure deeper settings.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Save and Finish</emphasis> will store the current configuration
level in the database and it will return to the previous screen in the
configuration hierarchy (to the immediate upper configuration level).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> will discard any configuration change to the
current configuration level and will return to the previous screen in the
configuration hierarchy.
                </para>
            </note>

            <section id="webservice-provider-network-transport">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás szolgáltatójának hálózati átvitele</title>
                <para>
                    In future the list of available network transports will be
increased. Currently only <emphasis>HTTP::SOAP</emphasis> and
<emphasis>HTTP::REST</emphasis> transports are available. Each transport has
different configuration options to setup and they might use different
frontend modules to configure them.
                </para>
                <para>
                    It is quite simple to configure the <emphasis>HTTP::SOAP</emphasis> protocol
as provider.  There are only two settings: <emphasis>Namespace</emphasis>
and <emphasis>Maximum message length</emphasis>. These fields are
required. The first one is a URI to give SOAP methods a context, reducing
ambiguities, and the second one is a field where you can specify the maximum
size (in bytes) for SOAP messages that OTRS will process.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás szolgáltatójának hálózati átvitele (HTTP::SOAP)</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-provider-transport-soap.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
                <para>
                    Adott esetben meghatározhat további válaszfejléceket is. Ezek használhatók
statikus fejlécértékek hozzáadásához az egyes válaszokhoz. Egyszerűen
kattintson a <emphasis>Válaszfejléc hozzáadása</emphasis> gombra, és töltse
ki mind a kulcs, mind az érték mezőket. Nincs korlát a további fejlécsorok
számára vonatkozóan.
                </para>
                <para>
                    For <emphasis>HTTP::REST</emphasis> the configuration might be a bit more
complicated, as it grows dynamically for each configured operation by
adding: <emphasis>Route mapping for Operation
'&lt;OperationName&gt;':</emphasis> and <emphasis>Valid request methods for
Operation '&lt;OperationName&gt;':</emphasis> settings to the default
transport settings <emphasis>Maximum message length:</emphasis> and
<emphasis>Send Keep-Alive:</emphasis>
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Útvonal leképezés a „&lt;Műveletnév&gt;” művelethez:</para>
                        <para>
                            Ebben a beállításban egy erőforrás útvonala van beállítva. Ezt az útvonalat
a webszolgáltatás igényei szerint kell meghatározni figyelembe véve, hogy az
útvonal a HTTP kérési módszerrel együtt határozza meg a végrehajtandó
általános felületi műveletet.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            Az útvonal tartalmazhat változókat „:&lt;Változónév&gt;” formájában. Minden
útvonalszöveg, amely megfelel a változónév pozícióján, hozzá lesz adva a
kérés hasznos terhéhez az ebben a beállításban meghatározott változónév
használatával.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            Példák:
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Útvonal leképezés: /Eroforras
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvényes kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvénytelen kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Útvonal leképezés: /Eroforras/:ID
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvényes kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/1
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/1?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    Mindkét esetben az ID = 1 lesz elküldve a műveletnek a hasznos teher
részeként. A második esetben a Param1 = Egy is hozzá lesz adva. A HTTP
kérési módszertől függően egyéb paraméterek is hozzá lesznek adva, ha azok
JSON szövegként érkeznek a kérés fejlécében.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvénytelen kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Útvonal leképezés: /Eroforras/EgyebEroforras/:ID/:Szin
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvényes kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras/1/Piros
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras/123/Kek?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    Az első példában ID = 1 és Szin = Piros, míg a másodikban ID = 123 és Szin =
Kek.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Érvénytelen kérések:</para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/1
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras/1
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/Proba/Eroforras/MasikEroforras/1?Param1=Egy
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    Az első példában a „/MasikEroforras” útvonal része, valamint a :Szin változó
hiányzik. A második példában csak a :Szin változó hiányzik.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Érvényes kérési módszerek a „&lt;Műveletnév&gt;” művelethez:</para>
                        <para>
                            A HTTP kérési módszerek az útvonal leképezéssel együtt használandó művelet
meghatározásához. Lehetséges lehetőségek: CONNECT, DELETE, GET, HEAD,
OPTIONS, PATCH, POST, PUT és TRACE.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            Teljesen különböző műveletek is megoszthatják pontosan ugyanazt a leképezési
útvonalat, de a kérési módszernek egyedinek kell lennie minden egyes
műveletnél azért, hogy minden kérésnél helyesen meghatározható legyen a
használandó művelet.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás szolgáltatójának hálózati átvitele (HTTP::REST)</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-provider-transport-rest.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-operation">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás művelete</title>
                <para>
                    The actions that can be performed when you are using OTRS as a provider are
called <emphasis>Operations</emphasis>. Each operation belongs to a
controller. Controllers are collections of operations or invokers, normally
operations from the same controller need similar settings and share the same
configuration dialog. But each operation can have independent configuration
dialogs if needed.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Name</emphasis>, <emphasis>Description</emphasis>,
<emphasis>Backend</emphasis> and <emphasis>Mappings</emphasis> are fields
that normally appear on every operation, other special fields can appear in
non default configuration dialogs to fulfill specific needs of the
operation.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Normális esetben két leképezés-beállítási szakasz van minden egyes
műveletnél: egy a bejövő adatokhoz, és egy másik a kimenő
adatokhoz. Különböző leképezési típusokat (háttérprogramokat) választhat
minden egyes leképezési irányhoz, mivel a beállításaik függetlenek
egymástól, valamint függetlenek a művelet háttérprogramjától is. A normál és
leggyakoribb gyakorlat az, hogy a művelet ugyanazt a leképezési típust
használja mindkét esetben (fordított beállítással). A teljes leképezési
beállítás külön képernyőn végezhető el, amely a leképezési típustól függ.
                </para>
                <para>
                    A művelet háttérprogramja előre ki van töltve és nem szerkeszthető. Akkor
fogja látni ezt a paramétert, amikor kiválasztja a műveletet a
webszolgáltatás szerkesztési képernyőjén. Ez a mező csak tájékoztató.
                </para>
                <para>
                    In the left part of the screen on the action column you have the options:
<emphasis>Go back to web service</emphasis> (discarding all changes since
the last save) and <emphasis>Delete</emphasis>.  If you click on the last
one, a dialog will open and ask you if you like to remove the
operation. Click on <emphasis>Delete</emphasis> button to confirm the
removal of the operation and its configuration or
<emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the delete dialog.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás művelete</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-operation.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-requester-transport">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás kérelmezőjének hálózati átvitele</title>
                <para>
                    The network transport configuration for the requester is similar to the
configuration for the provider. For the Requester
<emphasis>HTTP::SOAP</emphasis> network transport there are more fields to
be set.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Apart from the <emphasis>Endpoint</emphasis> (URI of the Remote System web
service interface to accept requests) and <emphasis>Namespace</emphasis>
which are required fields, you can also specify:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Kódolás (mint például utf-8, latin1, iso-8859-1, cp1250, stb.) a SOAP
üzeneteknél.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            SOAPAction Header: you can use this to send an empty or filled SOAPAction
header. Set to <emphasis>No</emphasis> and the SOAPAction header on the SOAP
message will be an empty string, or set to <emphasis>Yes</emphasis> to send
the SOAP action in Namespace#Action format and define the separator
(typically "/" for .Net web services and "#" for the REST).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Hitelesítés: a hitelesítési mechanizmus beállításához. Állítsa „-” értékre,
hogy semmilyen hitelesítést se használjon, vagy válasszon egyet a listából,
és meg fog jelenni a részletek mező.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Currently only the <emphasis>BasicAuth</emphasis> (HTTP) authentication
mechanism is implemented. You can decide whether or not to use it depending
on the Remote System configuration. If used, you must provide the User Name
and the Password to access the remote system.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        Ha a hitelesítéshez megad egy jelszót, akkor miután exportálja a
webszolgáltatást egy YAML-fájlba, ez a jelszó fel lesz fedve, és egyszerű
szöveges formátumban lesz kiírva a YAML-fájlon belül. Legyen tudatában
ennek, és tegye meg az óvintézkedéseket, ha szükséges.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás kérelmezőjének hálózati átvitele (HTTP::SOAP)</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-requester-transport-soap.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
                <para>
                    In the case of HTTP::REST, this configuration also grows dynamically
depending on the configured invokers by adding <emphasis>Controller mapping
for Invoker '&lt;InvokerName&gt;':</emphasis> and <emphasis>Valid request
command for Invoker '&lt;InvokerName&gt;':</emphasis> for each
invoke. Authentication and SSL options are similar to the ones in HTTP::SOAP
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Gép</para>
                        <para>
                            A távoli rendszer gépneve vagy IP-címe és portja. Ha nincs port megadva,
akkor a 80-as portot használja alapértelmezetten.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Vezérlő leképezés a „&lt;Meghívónév&gt;” meghívóhoz:</para>
                        <para>
                            Ebben a beállításban egy erőforrás útvonala van beállítva. Ezt az útvonalat
a távoli webszolgáltatás igényei szerint kell meghatározni, és követni kell
annak meghatározását.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            Az útvonal tartalmazhat változókat „:&lt;Változónév&gt;” formájában. Minden
változónév, amely illeszkedik az (elküldendő) jelenlegi adatokra, ki lesz
cserélve a megfelelő adatértékkel. Ezek az illesztett változónevek és
értékek el lesznek távolítva a jelenlegi adatokból. A HTTP kérési parancstól
függően a megmaradó adatok elküldhetők JSON-szövegként a kérés törzsében,
vagy lekérdezési paraméterekként az URI-n belül.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            Példák:
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            A következő adatoknál: Valtozo1 = Egy, Valtozo2 = Kettő, Valtozo3 = Három és
Valtozo4 = Négy.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Vezérlő leképezés: /Eroforras
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A cserék után:</para>
                                <para>/Eroforras</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Megmaradó adatok:</para>
                                <para> Valtozo1 = Egy, Valtozo2 = Kettő, Valtozo3 = Három és Valtozo4 = Négy</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Vezérlő leképezés: /Eroforras/:Valtozo1
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A cserék után:</para>
                                <para>/Eroforras/Egy</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Megmaradó adatok:</para>
                                <para> Valtozo2 = Kettő, Valtozo3 = Három és Valtozo4 = Négy</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                       <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <para>
                                Vezérlő leképezés:
/Eroforras/:Valtozo1?Param1=:Valtozo2&amp;Valtozo3=:Valtozo3
                            </para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A cserék után:</para>
                                <para>/Eroforras/Egy?Param1=Kettő&amp;Valtozo3=Három</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Megmaradó adatok:</para>
                                <para>Valtozo4 = Négy</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Érvényes kérési parancsok a „&lt;Meghívónév&gt;” meghívóhoz:</para>
                        <para>
                            Ez határozza meg a használandó HTTP kérési módszert, a lehetséges
lehetőségek: CONNECT, DELETE, GET, HEAD, OPTIONS, PATCH, POST, PUT és
TRACE. Ha nincs parancs kiválasztva, akkor az alapértelmezett parancsot
használja.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Alapértelmezett parancs</para>
                        <para>
                            Tartalékként van használva a meghatározott kérési parancs nélküli összes
meghívónál.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás kérelmezőjének hálózati átvitele (HTTP::REST)</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-requester-transport-rest.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-invoker">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás meghívója</title>
                <para>
                    The actions that can be performed when you are using OTRS as a requester are
called <emphasis>Invokers</emphasis>. Each invoker belongs to a controller
(controllers are collections of operations or invokers). Usually invokers
from the same controller need similar settings and share the same
configuration dialogs.  Each invoker can have independent configuration
dialogs if needed.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Name</emphasis>, <emphasis>Description</emphasis>,
<emphasis>Backend</emphasis> and <emphasis>Mappings</emphasis> are fields
that normally appear on every invoker. Additionally the list of event
triggers and other special fields can appear on non default configuration
dialogs to fulfill special needs of the invoker.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Normális esetben két leképezés-beállítási szakasz van minden egyes
meghívónál: egy a bejövő adatokhoz, és egy másik a kimenő
adatokhoz. Különböző leképezési típusokat (háttérprogramokat) választhat
minden egyes leképezési irányhoz, mivel a beállításaik függetlenek
egymástól, valamint függetlenek a meghívó háttérprogramjától is. A normál és
leggyakoribb gyakorlat az, hogy a meghívó ugyanazt a leképezési típust
használja mindkét esetben, fordított beállítással. A teljes leképezési
beállítás külön képernyőn végezhető el, amely a leképezési típustól függ.
                </para>
                <para>
                    A meghívó háttérprogramja előre ki van töltve és nem szerkeszthető. Akkor
fogja látni ezt a paramétert, amikor kiválasztja a meghívót a
webszolgáltatás szerkesztési képernyőjén. Ez a mező csak tájékoztató.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Event triggers are events within OTRS such as
<literal>TicketCreate</literal>, <literal>ArticleSend</literal>, etc. These
can act as triggers to execute the invoker. Each invoker needs to have at
least one event trigger registered, or the invoker will be useless, because
it will never be called. Additionally a set of rules (conditions) for each
event can be defined to have more control over the triggering of the events,
This rules depends on the data of the object associated with the event.  The
asynchronous property of the event triggers define if the OTRS process will
handle the invoker or if it will be delegated to the OTRS Daemon.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Az OTRS démon egy külön folyamatkészlet, amely feladatokat hajt végre a
háttérben. Ennek használatával maga az OTRS folyamat nem lesz érintett, ha a
távoli rendszernek hosszú ideig tart válaszolni, ha nem érhető el, vagy
hálózati problémák vannak. Ha nem használja az OTRS démont, akkor a
webszolgáltatások használata lelassíthatja vagy válaszképtelenné teheti az
OTRS keretrendszert. Ezért erősen ajánlott az aszinkron eseményaktiválók
használata, amilyen gyakran csak lehetséges.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    To add an Event trigger, first select the event family from the first list,
then the event name from the second list, then set the asynchronous property
(if unchecked means that the event trigger will not be asynchronous) and
finally click on the plus button. A new event trigger will be created and it
will be listed on the invoker <emphasis>Event Triggers</emphasis> list.
                </para>
                <para>
                    From the <emphasis>Event Triggers</emphasis> list each events shows if it
contains conditions or not.  The edit button next to the condition property
allows to add or edit the current conditions of the event.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To delete an Event trigger, simply locate the event trigger to be deleted in
the <emphasis>Event Triggers</emphasis> list and click on the trash icon at
the end of the row. This will open a dialog that asks you if you are sure to
delete the event trigger.  Click <emphasis>Delete</emphasis> to remove the
event trigger from the list, or <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the
dialog.
                </para>
                <para>
                    In the left part of the screen on the action column you have the options:
<emphasis>Go back to web service</emphasis> (discarding all changes since
the last save) and "Delete".  If you click on the last one, a dialog will
emerge and ask you if you like to remove the invoker. Click on the
<emphasis>Delete</emphasis> button to confirm the removal of the invoker and
its configuration or <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> to close the delete dialog.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás meghívója</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-invoker.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-invoker-event">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás meghívó esemény</title>
                <para>
                    Sometimes defining an event to trigger an invoker could result in many
unnecessary or wrong request to a remote server. Event conditions could be
set to restrict the triggering of the invoker in such cases.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To access the event settings screen where the conditions can be defined is
necessary to be in the invoker screen and from there click on the edit icon
next to the condition status on the event where this conditions should take
effect.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Within the event settings screen in the action bar there is a button to go
back to the invoker screen as well as a button to remove all the event
conditions.  By default the screen is pre-populated with the first
condition. Update the Type of linkings between conditions if more than one
condition is planned, then change the Type of linking from
<emphasis>Condition 1</emphasis> if more than one field is planned. Both
linking fields accepts <emphasis>and</emphasis>, <emphasis>or</emphasis> or
<emphasis>xor</emphasis> as values.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Fill the <emphasis>Field</emphasis> name, set the matching type
(<emphasis>String</emphasis> for exact match, <emphasis>Regexp</emphasis>
for regular expression or <emphasis>Validation Module</emphasis>) and set
Value to match (in case of <emphasis>Validation Module</emphasis> the full
class name like:
<literal>Kernel::GenericInterface::Event::Validation::ValidateDemo</literal>).
                </para>
                <para>
                    To add more fields to the condition, click on the <emphasis>+</emphasis>
button in the fields header. To remove a field, click on the
<emphasis>-</emphasis> button in the field row. It is necessary to keep at
least one field per condition.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To add more conditions clock on the button below the last condition box.  To
remove remove a condition, click on the <emphasis>-</emphasis> button in the
condition header.  It is necessary to keep at least one condition in the
set. To remove all conditions use the button in the sidebar.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás meghívó esemény</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-invoker-event.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-mapping">
                <title>Webszolgáltatás leképezése</title>
                <para>
                    Vannak olyan esetek, ahol át kell alakítania az adatokat az egyik
formátumról egy másik (adatszerkezet leképezése vagy megváltoztatása), mert
normális esetben egy webszolgáltatást arra használnak, hogy kölcsönhatásba
lépjen egy távoli rendszerrel, amely nagyon valószínű, hogy nem egy másik
OTRS rendszer és/vagy nem tudja megérteni az OTRS adatszerkezeteit és
értékeit. Ezekben az esetekben néhány vagy az összes adatot meg kell
változtatni, és néha még az értékek (kulcsok) neveit is, vagy akár a teljes
szerkezetet annak érdekében, hogy egyezzen a másik végen elvárt adatokkal. A
feladat végrehajtásához van jelen az általános felület leképező rétege.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Each Remote System has it own data structures and it is possible to create
new mapping modules for each case (e.g. there is a customized mapping module
for SAP Solution Manager shipped with OTRS), but it is not always
necessary.  The module <literal>Mapping::Simple</literal> should cover most
of the mapping needs.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        When <literal>Mapping::Simple</literal> does not cover all mapping needs for
a web service, a new mapping module should be created. To learn more about
how to create new mapping modules please consult the OTRS Development
Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    Ez a modul alkalmat ad arra, hogy alapértelmezett értékeket állítson be az
egyes kulcsok vagy értékek leképezéséhez a teljes kommunikációs adatoknál.
                </para>
                <para>
                    A képernyő elején egy általános szakaszt fog látni, ahol azokat az
alapértelmezett szabályokat állíthatja be, amelyeket alkalmazni kell az
összes leképezetlen kulcsnál és értéknél. Három lehetőség érhető el, ezek a
lehetőségek vannak alább felsorolva:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Megtartás (változatlanul hagyás): semmilyen módon sem nyúl a kulcsokhoz vagy
értékekhez.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Mellőzés (kulcs/érték pár eldobása): amikor ezt a kulcson alkalmazzák, akkor
törli a kulcsot és az értéket, mert amikor egy kulcs törlődik, akkor annak
következtében a hozzárendelt érték is törölve lesz. Amikor ezt az értéken
alkalmazzák, akkor csak az érték törlődik megtartva a kulcsot, amely most
már egy üres értékhez lesz hozzárendelve.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Leképezés (a megadott kulcs vagy érték használata alapértelmezettként): egy
meghatározott leképezési szabály nélküli összes kulcs és/vagy érték ezt
fogja alapértelmezettként használni. Amikor ezt a lehetőséget választja,
akkor egy új szövegmező fog megjelenni az alapértelmezett beállításához.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    Clicking on the <emphasis>+</emphasis> button for new key map, will display
a new box for a single mapping configuration. You can add as many key
mappings as needed. Just click on the <emphasis>+</emphasis> button again
and a new mapping box will appear below the existing one. From this mapping
boxes you can define a map for a single key, with the next options:
                </para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Pontos érték(ek): a régi kulcsszöveg meg lesz változtatva egy újra, ha a
régi kulcs pontosan egyezik.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Reguláris kifejezés: a kulcsszöveg le lesz cserélve egy reguláris kifejezési
szabályt követve.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para>
                    Pressing the new value map <emphasis>+</emphasis> button will display a new
row for a value map.  Here it is also possible to define rules for each
value to be mapped with the same options as for the key map (Exact value and
Regular expression). You can add as many values to map as needed, and if you
want to delete one of them, just click on the <emphasis>-</emphasis> button
for each mapping value row.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Deleting the complete key mapping section (box) is possible, just push on
the <emphasis>-</emphasis> button located on the up right corner of each box
that you want to delete.
                </para>
                <para>
                    If you need to delete a complete mapping configuration: go back to the
corresponding operation or invoker screen, look for the mapping direction
that you select before and set its value to <emphasis>-</emphasis>, and save
the configuration to apply changes.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Webszolgáltatás leképezése</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/genericinterface/genericinterface-webservice-mapping.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                </para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
