<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-package-manager">
<title>パッケージ・マネージャー</title>

<para>
管理者ページ上で「パッケージ管理」リンクを使用すると、OTRSの機能性を拡張するパッケージをインストールし管理することができます(下図参照)。OTRSリポジトリから利用可能な拡張に関する議論は<link
linkend="application">追加アプリケーション</link>セクションを御覧ください。
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>パッケージ・マネージャー</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
パッケージ・マネージャは、それらのバージョン番号と一緒に、サーバに現在インストールした OTRS addonパッケージを示します。
</para>

<para><emphasis>オンライン・レポジトリ</emphasis>セクションにあるレポジトリを選択し、<emphasis>リポジトリ情報の更新</emphasis>ボタンをクリックすることによって、リモート・ホストからパッケージをインストールすることができます。利用可能なパッケージが対応するテーブルに表示されます。
画面右側には利用可能なパッケージを表示します。パッケージをインストールするために<emphasis>インストール</emphasis>をクリックします。インストレーション後、パッケージは<emphasis>ローカル・レポジトリ</emphasis>セクションを表示します。
</para>

<para>
To update an installed package, the list of available packages in the online
repository will show <emphasis>Update</emphasis> in the Action column for
any package that has a higher version than the one that is installed
locally. Just click Update and it will install the new package version on
your system.
</para>

<para>
OTRSシステムがインターネットに接続されないような場合、ローカル・ディスクにダウンロードしたそれらのパッケージもインストールすることもできます。アクション・サイドバー上の<emphasis>ブラウズ</emphasis>をクリックし、あなたのディスク内の.opmファイルを選択します。<emphasis>開く</emphasis>を、それから<emphasis>パッケージをインストール</emphasis>をクリックします。インストレーションの完了後、パッケージは<emphasis>レポジトリ</emphasis>セクションに表示されます。設置が終わった後、パッケージは<emphasis>のローカルのリポジトリ</emphasis>セクションに表示されます。既にインストールされているパッケージの更新のために同じステップを使用することができます。
</para>

<para>
In special cases, you might want to configure the Package Manager, e.g., to
use a proxy or to use a local repository. Just take a look at the available
options in SysConfig under <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Section_Core_Package">Core::Package</link>.
</para>
    <section id="adminarea-package-manager-upgrade-all">
        <title>インストールされているパッケージを全て更新する</title>
        <para>
            Since OTRS 6, a new button labeled <literal>"Update all installed
packages"</literal> has been added to the sidebar of the package manager
screen. When this button is pressed, an OTRS Daemon task will be scheduled
to update all packages. Alternatively, this action can be also issued from
the command line interface by using the
<literal>Admin::Package::UpgradeAll</literal> console command.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Button</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-button.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            This feature reads the information of all defined package repositories and
determines if there is a new version for every installed package in the
system and calculates the correct order to update the packages respecting
all other package dependencies, even if new versions of existing packages
require new packages not yet installed in the system.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                If there are packages installed that do not have a corresponding repository
defined in the system, they can not be updated by this feature and will be
marked as failed (due to the missing on-line repository).
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            When the process to update all packages is running, a notification bar is
added to the package manager screen for easier identification. When
notification link is clicked, a progress summary is displayed with the
current progress. Also, when the process is running package actions such as
"Install", "Update", "Uninstall" and "ReInstall" some actions on the screen
might be temporarily disabled in order to avoid conflicts.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages In Progress Notification</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-process-notification.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            When the process finishes (only if it was started in the graphical user
interface) the progress notification will change to indicate the new state:
it becomes green if all packages was correctly updated or red if there where
any failures. Clicking on this notification will show the final summary. In
the summary table, a tooltip for the status column of every package can
indicate more details about the state. After closing this window, the
package manager screen will refresh to show the new version of the installed
packages.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Summary</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-summary.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </section>
</section>
