<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-package-manager">
<title>Package Manager</title>

<para>
Using the "Package Manager" link on the Admin page, you can install and manage packages that extend the functionality of OTRS (see figure below). See the <link linkend="application">Additional applications</link> section for a discussion on the extensions that are available from the OTRS repositories.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Package Manager</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
The Package Manager shows the OTRS addon packages you currently have installed on your server, together with their version numbers.
</para>

<para>You can install packages from a remote host by selecting the repository in the <emphasis>Online Repository</emphasis> section, and clicking the <emphasis>Update repository information</emphasis> button. The available packages are displayed in the corresponding table. The right side of the screen shows the available packages. To install a package, click on <emphasis>Install</emphasis>. After installation, the package is displayed in the <emphasis>Local Repository</emphasis> section.
</para>

<para>
To update an installed package, the list of available packages in the online repository will show <emphasis>Update</emphasis> in the Action column for any package that has a higher version than the one that is installed locally. Just click Update and it will install the new package version on your system.
</para>

<para>
In some cases, such as when your OTRS system is not connected to the Internet, you can also install those packages that you have downloaded to a local disk. Click the <emphasis>Browse</emphasis> button on the Actions side bar, and select the .opm file of the package on your disk. Click <emphasis>Open</emphasis> and then <emphasis>Install Package</emphasis>. After the installation has been completed, the package is displayed in the <emphasis>Local Repository</emphasis> section. You can use the same steps for updating a package that is already installed.
</para>

<para>
In special cases, you might want to configure the Package Manager, e.g., to use a proxy or to use a local repository. Just take a look at the available options in SysConfig under <link linkend="ConfigReference_Section_Core_Package">Core::Package</link>.
</para>
    <section id="adminarea-package-manager-upgrade-all">
        <title>Update all installed packages</title>
        <para>
            Since OTRS 6, a new button labeled <literal>"Update all installed packages"</literal> has been added to the
            sidebar of the package manager screen. When this button is pressed, an OTRS Daemon task will be scheduled to
            update all packages. Alternatively, this action can be also issued from the command line interface by using
            the <literal>Admin::Package::UpgradeAll</literal> console command.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Button</title>
            <screenshot>
                 <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-button.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </figure>
        <para>
            This feature reads the information of all defined package repositories and determines if there is a new
            version for every installed package in the system and calculates the correct order to update the packages
            respecting all other package dependencies, even if new versions of existing packages require new packages
            not yet installed in the system.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                If there are packages installed that do not have a corresponding repository defined in the system, they
                can not be updated by this feature and will be marked as failed (due to the missing on-line
                repository).
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            When the process to update all packages is running, a notification bar is added to the package manager
            screen for easier identification. When notification link is clicked, a progress summary is displayed with
            the current progress. Also, when the process is running package actions such as "Install", "Update",
            "Uninstall" and "ReInstall" some actions on the screen might be temporarily disabled in order to avoid
            conflicts.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages In Progress Notification</title>
            <screenshot>
                 <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-process-notification.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </figure>
        <para>
            When the process finishes (only if it was started in the graphical user interface) the progress notification
            will change to indicate the new state: it becomes green if all packages was correctly updated or red if
            there where any failures. Clicking on this notification will show the final summary. In the summary table, a
            tooltip for the status column of every package can indicate more details about the state. After closing this
            window, the package manager screen will refresh to show the new version of the installed packages.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Summary</title>
            <screenshot>
                 <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-summary.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </figure>
    </section>
</section>
