<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-package-manager">
<title>软件包管理器</title>

<para>
Using the <emphasis>Package Manager</emphasis> link on the Admin page, you
can install and manage packages that extend the functionality of OTRS (see
figure below). See the <link linkend="application">Additional
applications</link> section for a discussion on the extensions that are
available from the OTRS repositories.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>软件包管理器</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
软件包管理器显示服务器上当前已经安装了的OTRS插件软件包以及它们的版本号。
</para>

<para>你可以从远程主机安装软件包，选择<emphasis>在线软件仓库</emphasis>，点击<emphasis>更新软件仓库信息</emphasis>，则会显示可用的软件。窗口右侧显示可用的软件包。要安装一个软件包，点击<emphasis>安装</emphasis>即可。安装完成后，这个软件包就会在<emphasis>本地软件仓库</emphasis>部分显示。
</para>

<para>
To update an installed package, the list of available packages in the online
repository will show <emphasis>Update</emphasis> in the Action column for
any package that has a higher version than the one that is installed
locally. Just click <emphasis>Update</emphasis> and it will install the new
package version on your system.
</para>

<para>
在某些情况下，比如你的OTRS系统无法连接到Internet，你还可以安装下载到本地磁盘的软件包。点击左侧的<emphasis>浏览</emphasis>按钮，并选择磁盘上软件包的.opm文件，点击<emphasis>打开</emphasis>，再点击<emphasis>安装软件包</emphasis>按钮。在安装完成后，这个软件包就会在<emphasis>本地软件仓库</emphasis>部分显示。同样可以用这个方法来更新一个已经安装的软件包。
</para>

<para>
在特殊情况下，你可能需要配置软件包管理器，例如使用代理或使用本地存储库。 只需看一下系统配置中的<link
linkend="ConfigReference_Section_Core_Package">Core::Package</link>下的可用选项。
</para>
    <section id="adminarea-package-manager-upgrade-all">
        <title>更新所有已安装的软件包</title>
        <para>
            Since OTRS 6, a new button labeled <emphasis>Update all installed
packages</emphasis> has been added to the sidebar of the package manager
screen. When this button is pressed, an OTRS Daemon task will be scheduled
to update all packages. Alternatively, this action can be also issued from
the command line interface by using the
<literal>Admin::Package::UpgradeAll</literal> console command.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Button</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-button.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            This feature reads the information of all defined package repositories and
determines if there is a new version for every installed package in the
system and calculates the correct order to update the packages respecting
all other package dependencies, even if new versions of existing packages
require new packages not yet installed in the system.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                If there are packages installed that do not have a corresponding repository
defined in the system, they can not be updated by this feature and will be
marked as failed (due to the missing on-line repository).
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            When the process to update all packages is running, a notification bar is
added to the package manager screen for easier identification. When
notification link is clicked, a progress summary is displayed with the
current progress. Also, when the process is running package actions such as
"Install", "Update", "Uninstall" and "ReInstall" some actions on the screen
might be temporarily disabled in order to avoid conflicts.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages In Progress Notification</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-process-notification.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            When the process finishes (only if it was started in the graphical user
interface) the progress notification will change to indicate the new state:
it becomes green if all packages was correctly updated or red if there where
any failures. Clicking on this notification will show the final summary. In
the summary table, a tooltip for the status column of every package can
indicate more details about the state. After closing this window, the
package manager screen will refresh to show the new version of the installed
packages.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Update All Installed Packages Summary</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-summary.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </section>
</section>
