<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="upgrading">
    <title>Upgrading OTRS</title>

    <note>
        <para>
            It is highly recommended to perform a test update on a separate testing machine first.
        </para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Upgrading from an earlier version of OTRS 6</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    You can upgrade directly from any previous to the latest available patch level release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Upgrading from OTRS 5</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    You can upgrade from any OTRS 5 patch level to the latest available OTRS 6 patch level release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Upgrading from OTRS 4 or earlier</term>
            <listitem>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        You cannot upgrade from OTRS 4 or earlier directly to OTRS 6.
                        Instead, full updates to all available minor versions have to be made sequentially instead.
                        For example, if you come from OTRS 3.0, you first have to perform a full update to OTRS 3.1,
                        then to 3.2, 3.3, 4, 5 and finally to OTRS 6.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 1: Stop all relevant services and the OTRS Daemon</title>

        <para>
        Please make sure there are no more running services or cron jobs that try to access OTRS.
        This will depend on your service configuration, here is an example:
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
root> /etc/init.d/cron stop
root> /etc/init.d/postfix stop
root> /etc/init.d/apache stop
            ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <para>
        Stop OTRS cron jobs and the daemon (in this order):
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/Cron.sh stop
otrs> bin/otrs.Daemon.pl stop
            ]]></screen>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 2: Backup files and database</title>

        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAuto.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                <listitem><para><filename>var/*</filename></para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>as well as the database</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <warning>
            <para>Don't proceed without a complete backup of your system.</para>
        </warning>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
    <title>Step 3: Install the new release (tar or RPM)</title>

        <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 3.1: With the tarball:</title>

            <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd /opt
root> mv otrs otrs-old
root> tar -xzf otrs-x.x.x.tar.gz
root> mv otrs-x.x.x otrs
            ]]></screen>

            <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Restore old configuration files</title>

                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAuto.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section role="NotInToc">
                <title>Restore article data</title>

                <para>
                    If you configured OTRS to store article data in the filesystem you have to restore the <filename>article</filename> folder to <filename>/opt/otrs/var/</filename>
                    or the folder specified in the SysConfig.
                </para>
            </section>


            <section role="NotInToc">
                <title>Restore already installed default statistics</title>

                <para>
                    If you have additional packages with default statistics you have to restore the stats xml files with the suffix <filename>*.installed</filename> to <filename>/opt/otrs/var/stats</filename>.
                </para>
                <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd OTRS-BACKUP/var/stats
root> cp *.installed /opt/otrs/var/stats
                ]]></screen>
            </section>

            <section role="NotInToc">
                <title>Set file permissions</title>

                <para>
                    Please execute the following command as root user to set the file and directory permissions for OTRS:
                </para>

                <para>
                <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd /opt/otrs/
root> bin/otrs.SetPermissions.pl
                ]]></screen>
                </para>

                <para>
                    It will try to detect the correct user and group settings needed for your setup.
                </para>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Step 3.2: With the RPM:</title>
            <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
root> rpm -Uvh otrs-x.x.x.-01.rpm
            ]]></screen>
            </para>

            <para>
                In this case the RPM update automatically restores the old configuration files and sets file permissions.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 4: Run the migration script</title>

        <para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> scripts/DBUpdate-to-6.pl
        ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <para>
            This script will perform many checks on your system and give you advice on how to install
            missing Perl modules etc., if that is required. If all checks succeeded, the neccessary migration steps
            will be performed. Please also run this script in case of patch level updates.
        </para>

        <note>
            <para>
                The migration script will ask you to set a time zone for OTRS if needed. It is very important that you set
                the correct time zone (<literal>OTRSTimeZone</literal>) for data storage and keep it,
                otherwise date and time of data added after the upgrade (tickets, articles, etc.) will be stored
                with a different time zone than your pre-existing data, leading to inconsistent output.
            </para>
            <para>
                For new systems, using <literal>UTC</literal> is recommended, as users can have different personal
                time zones for working with the OTRS application. For existing, migrated systems, a different
                <literal>OTRSTimeZone</literal> should be used if the underlying operating system is not configured to
                <literal>UTC</literal> or if OTRS previously used a time offset.
            </para>
        </note>

        <warning>
            <para>
                Do not continue the upgrading process if this script did not work properly for you.
                Otherwise malfunction or data loss may occur.
            </para>
        </warning>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 5: Restart your services</title>

        <para>
            This will depend on your service configuration, here is an example:
        </para>

        <para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
root> /etc/init.d/apache start
root> /etc/init.d/postfix start
root> /etc/init.d/cron start
        ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <para>
            Now you can log into your system. Please note that the OTRS Daemon is started only in a later step.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 6: Check installed packages</title>
        <para>
            The OTRS 5 packages are NOT compatible with OTRS 6 and have to be updated.
        </para>
        <para>
            The following packages are automatically uninstalled during the upgrade process, if they where installed
            before:
        </para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>OTRSAppointmentCalendar</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>OTRSTicketNumberCounterDatabase</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>OTRSAdvancedTicketSplit</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>OTRSGenericInterfaceInvokerEventFilter</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 7: Start the OTRS Daemon and cron job</title>

        <para>
            The OTRS daemon is responsible for handling any asynchronous and recurring tasks in OTRS.
            The daemon and its keepalive cron job must be started as the <literal>otrs</literal> user.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> /opt/otrs/bin/otrs.Daemon.pl start
otrs> /opt/otrs/bin/Cron.sh start
            ]]></screen>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 8: Update system registration (optional)</title>
        <para>
            If the system is already registered with OTRS Group, it is strongly recommended to update
            the registration information at this time. This will update the registered version of
            the system (among other changes) in the OTRS Group records, to help with solving issues that
            could potentially be caused by the upgrade.
        </para>
        <para>
            If you don't update the registration information manually, it will be done automatically
            on a regular basis, but this could happen some hours or days later. During this
            period it might be possible to get wrong information from cloud services like the
            <emphasis role="bold">OTRS Business Solution™</emphasis> availability check.
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Registration::UpdateSend --force
otrs> bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Cache::Delete
            ]]></screen>
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
