<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-package-manager">
<title>Менеджер пакетов</title>

<para>
Using the "Package Manager" link on the Admin page, you can install and
manage packages that extend the functionality of OTRS (see figure
below). See the <link linkend="application">Additional applications</link>
section for a discussion on the extensions that are available from the OTRS
repositories.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Менеджер пакетов</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
Менеджер Пакетов позволяет просмотреть пакеты расширения OTRS вместе с
номерами их версий, установленные на сервере в данный момент.
</para>

<para>Пакеты можно установить из удаленного хоста, для этого, в разделе
<emphasis>Онлайн Репозиторий</emphasis> нужно выбрать репозиторий и нажать
кнопку <emphasis>Обновить информацию из репозитория</emphasis>. Все
доступные пакеты будут отображены в соответствующей таблице. В правой части
страницы отображаются доступные пакеты. Чтобы установить пакет, нажмите на
ссылку <emphasis>Установить</emphasis>. После установки пакет будет
отображаться в разделе <emphasis>Local Repository</emphasis>.
</para>

<para>
Для обновления установленных пакетов можно воспользоваться списком доступных
пакетов из он-лайн репозитория. В колонке "действие" для каждого из пакетов,
который имеет более высокую версию, чем установленная сейчас, нажмите кнопку
<emphasis>Обновить</emphasis>. Просто нажмите на кнопку "Обновить", и новый
пакет будет обновлен.
</para>

<para>
В некоторых случаях, например, когда ваша OTRS-система не подключена к
Интернету, можно установить пакеты, которые были заранее загружены на
локальный диск. Нажмите кнопку <emphasis> Обзор</emphasis> на боковой панели
и выберите. opm-файл на жестком диске. Нажмите <emphasis> Открыть
</emphasis>, а затем <emphasis> Установить пакет</emphasis>. После установки
пакет отображается в разделе <emphasis>Локальный
Репозиторий</emphasis>. Проделайте те же действия для того чтобы обновить
уже установленный пакет.
</para>

<para>
In special cases, you might want to configure the Package Manager, e.g., to
use a proxy or to use a local repository. Just take a look at the available
options in SysConfig under <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Section_Core_Package">Core::Package</link>.
</para>
    <section id="adminarea-package-manager-upgrade-all">
        <title>Upgrade all installed packages</title>
        <para>
            Since OTRS 6, a new button labeled <literal>"Upgrade all installed
packages"</literal> has been added to the sidebar of the package manager
screen. When this button is pressed, an OTRS Daemon task will be scheduled
to upgrade all packages. Alternatively, this action can be also issued from
the command line interface by using the
<literal>Admin::Package::UpgradeAll</literal> console command.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Upgrade All Installed Packages Button</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-button.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            This feature reads the information of all defined package repositories and
determines if there is a new version for every installed package in the
system and calculates the correct order to upgrade the packages respecting
all other package dependencies, even if new versions of existing packages
require new packages not yet installed in the system.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                If there are packages installed that do not have a corresponding repository
defined in the system, they can not be upgraded by this feature and will be
marked as failed (due to the missing on-line repository).
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            When the process to upgrade all packages is running, a notification bar is
added to the package manager screen for easier identification. When
notification link is clicked, a progress summary is displayed with the
current progress. Also, when the process is running package actions such as
"Install", "Upgrade", "Uninstall" and "ReInstall" some actions on the screen
might be temporarily disabled in order to avoid conflicts.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Upgrade All Installed Packages In Progress Notification</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-process-notification.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        <para>
            When the process finishes (only if it was started in the graphical user
interface) the progress notification will change to indicate the new state:
it becomes green if all packages was correctly upgraded or red if there
where any failures. Clicking on this notification will show the final
summary. In the summary table, a tooltip for the status column of every
package can indicate more details about the state. After closing this
window, the package manager screen will refresh to show the new version of
the installed packages.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>Package Manager Upgrade All Installed Packages Summary</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager-upgradeall-summary.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </section>
</section>
