<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-salutations-signatures-attachments-and-answers">
    <title>Приветствия, Подписи, Вложения и Шаблоны</title>

    <section id="adminarea-salutations">
        <title>Приветсвтия</title>

        <para>
            A salutation is a text module for a template. Salutations can be linked to
one or more queues, as described in the section about <link
linkend="adminarea-queue">queues</link>. A salutation is used only if a
ticket from a queue the salutation is linked to, is answered. To manage the
different salutations of your system, use the "Salutations" link of the
admin area (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Управления приветствиями</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-salutation.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            После установки в системе есть одно предопределенное приветствие: "system
standard salutation (en)".
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new salutation, press the button <literal>Add
salutation</literal>, provide the required data and submit it (see figure
below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Добавление нового приветствия</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-salutation.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            В приветствиях можно использовать переменные. Когда вы отвечаете на заявку,
имена переменных будут заменены на их значения.
        </para>

        <para>
            Различные переменные, которые можно использовать в ответах приведены в
нижней части экрана приветствия. Если вы используете, например, переменную
&lt;OTRS_LAST_NAME&gt; то в ответ будет включена фамилия отправителя заявки.
        </para>

        <note>
            <para>
                Как и в случае с другими сущностями системы OTRS, приветствия не можно
удалять, только деактивировать их, установив параметр Действительный в
значение <emphasis>не действительный</emphasis> или <emphasis>не
действительный-временно</emphasis>.
            </para>
        </note>

    </section>

    <section id="adminarea-signatures">
        <title>Подписи</title>

        <para>
            Another text module for a template is the signature. Signatures can be
linked to a queue, as described in the section about the <link
linkend="adminarea-queue">queues</link>. Please note that a signature will
only be appended to a template text, if it has previously been linked to a
queue. You can manage the signatures in your system by accessing the
"Signatures" link of the Admin page, (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Управление подписями</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-signatures.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            В новой, только установленной системе OTRS есть одна предустановленная
подпись:  "system standard signature (en)".
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new signature, press the button <literal>Add
signature</literal>, provide the needed data and submit it (see figure
below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Добавление новой подписи</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-signature.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            Как и приветствия, подписи также могут содержать динамический контент,
например, имя и фамилию агента, который отвечает на заявку, а также могут
использоваться переменные для замены текста подписи каждой
заявки. Переменные, которые можно использовать ищите в нижней части страницы
с подписями. Если вы, к примеру, включаете переменную &lt;OTRS_LAST_NAME&gt;
то она будет заменена фамилией агента, который отвечает на заявку.
        </para>

        <note>
            <para>
                Как и в случае с приветствиями, подписи не могут быть удалены, только
деактивированы путем установки параметра Действительный в значения
<emphasis>не действительный</emphasis> или <emphasis>не
действительный-временно</emphasis>.
            </para>
        </note>

    </section>

    <section id="adminarea-attachments">
        <title>Вложения</title>

        <para>
            You can also optionally add one or more attachments to a template. If the
template is selected, the attachments will be attached to the message in the
compose screen. If necessary, the agent can remove the attachment from an
individual template before sending it to the customer.
        </para>

        <para>
            Through the "Attachment" link of the Admin page, you can load the
attachments into the database of the system (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Управление вложениями</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-attachment.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new attachment, press the button <literal>Add
attachment</literal>, provide the required data and submit it (see figure
below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Добавление нового вложения</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-attachment.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            If an attachment is stored it can be linked to one or more templates. Click
on the <literal>Attachment &lt;-&gt; Templates</literal> link of the Admin
page (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Связать вложения с шаблонами.</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-attachment-template.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            To associate different attachments with a specific template and vice versa,
click on the corresponding template name or attachment (see below the
Figures 4.29 and 4.30, respectively).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Изменить связь Вложения с Шаблоном</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-attachment-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Изменить связь Шаблона с Вложением</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-attachment-relations2.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section id="adminarea-Templates">
        <title>Шаблоны</title>

        <para>
            Для ускорения работы в OTRS и стандартизовать вид ответов, можно задать
шаблоны. Шаблон может быть связан с одной или несколькими очередями и
наоборот.
        </para>

        <para>
            Существует несколько различных видов шаблонов, которые могут быть
использованы в различных местах в OTRS и в различных целях. Ниже приведен
список доступных типов шаблонов:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist mark="round">
            <listitem>
                <para>Ответ: Будет использоваться в качестве ответа на заявку</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Создать: Будет использоваться в качестве Телефонной Заявки или Email заявки</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Переслать: Используется для пересылки сообщения кому-то другому</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Телефонный звонок: Для регистрации входящих и исходящих звонков агентом</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    ProcessDialog: To be used in the Process activity dialogs (field
&quot;Article&quot; contains the template selection)
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>
            Answer templates can be accessed in two ways, from the ticket zoom screen in
the article menu, or in a quicker fashion: from any ticket overview large
screen such as Status View or Ticket View. For a fresh OTRS installation,
the "empty answer" template (Answer) is set as the default for every queue.
        </para>

        <para>
            As soon as Forward templates are added and assigned to the queues, the
"Forward" button in ticket zoom (that normally leads to an empty text
forward screen) will change into a selection control. This selection is
filled with the added Forward templates, and by choosing one of the
templates, the forward screen will be shown pre-filled with the template
text and attachments (similar to the reply selection box with the Answer
templates).
        </para>

        <para>
            Creating templates of type Create and PhoneCall will make visible the "Text
Template" selection box in their respective screens, and choosing a template
for the list will populate the "Text" and "Attachment" fields (if available
in the template). Notice that any previous change in the text or attachments
will be overwritten by selecting a template.
        </para>

        <para>
            Clicking the "Templates" link on the Admin page brings you to the Template
management screen (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Управление шаблонами</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-template.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new template, click on the <literal>Add template</literal>
button, provide the required data (make sure to select the appropriate
template type) and submit it (see figure below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Добавление шаблона</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-template.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            To add/remove templates to one or more queues, click on the "Templates
&lt;-&gt; Queues" link on the Admin page (see figure below). You can also
use filters to get information regarding a specific entity.
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Настройка Шаблонов для Очередей</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-template-queue.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            To define the different templates that will be available for a queue and
vice versa, click on the corresponding template or queue (see figures
below).
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Изменить связь Очереди с Шаблоном</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-queue-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Изменить связь Шаблона с Очередью</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-queue-relations2.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            When choosing a template, additional information could be added to the
template text, this depends on the template type.
        </para>
        <para>
            PhoneCall and Create templates do not add any content to the template
text. However, New Email Ticket screen adds the queue assigned signature to
the resulting email body (this screen has a separated box to visualize the
signature).
        </para>
        <para>
            Answer templates text when selected also include the salutation associated
with the queue, followed by the text of the template, then the quoted ticket
text, and finally the signature associated with the queue.
        </para>
        <para>
            Forward templates are similar to Answer templates, but they do not include
the salutation part.
        </para>

    </section>

</section>
