<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="configuration">
<title>系统配置</title>

<section id="directories-and-configfiles">
<title>OTRS 配置文件</title>

<para>
All OTRS configuration files are stored in the directory
<filename>Kernel</filename> and in its subdirectories. There is no need to
manually change any other file than <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>,
because the rest of the files will be changed when the system gets
updated. Just copy the configuration parameters from other files into
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> and change them as per your
needs. This file will never be touched during the update process, so your
manual changes are safe.
</para>

<para>
The configuration can be rebuilt either manually by executing <literal>perl
bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Config::Rebuild</literal> or automatically by the
installer, package operations (install, update, reinstall and uninstall),
etc. All <filename>.xml</filename> files located in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/XML/</filename> are parsed and their content
is transferred to the OTRS database. Most of the <filename>.xml</filename>
files which are part of this directory by default belong to OTRS Free, but
OTRS Free Features such as FAQ or Survey (or any other OTRS extension) will
add their own configuration files to this directory as well.
</para>

<para>
要对配置进行任何更改，需要进行部署。
部署进程将从OTRS数据库中提取所有设置和相关值，将其转换为OTRS可以自然理解的格式，并将其放入<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename>中。
</para>

<para>
如果访问OTRS
Web界面，则包含在文件<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename>、<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZACL.pm</filename>
(如果有)、 <filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZProcessManagement.pm</filename>
(如果有) 和任何其他自定义<filename> .pm </filename>文件将按字母顺序进行评估。
这些文件由图形用户界面用于缓存目的，不应手动更改。
最后，将解析包含单个设置和手动更改的配置参数的文件<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>。
按照此顺序读取这些配置文件，确保系统正确地考虑了您的特定配置设置。
</para>

</section>

<section id="sysconfig">
<title>通过WEB界面配置系统</title>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>系统配置的图形界面</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-systemconfiguration.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
OTRS 免费版目前带来了1700多种配置设置，并且有不同的方法快速访问特定的配置设置。 使用全文搜索，通过一个或多个关键字扫描所有的配置设置。
全文搜索不仅搜索配置设置的名称，还可以搜索描述和值。 这样可以很容易地找到配置元素，即使不知道它的名称。
</para>

<para>
此外，每个配置设置由类别和导航组分类。 导航组是主导航树中的单个元素。 通过选择其中一个导航条目，将显示分配给所选组的所有设置。
只要没有安装扩展名，类别选择就会被自动隐藏，但是一旦安装了一个包含自己的配置设置的软件包（如FAQ知识库或调查），就会显示类别选择。
选择一个类别使主导航树仅显示属于所选类别的导航组。
</para>

<para>
All configuration settings are shown as read only by default. To edit a
setting, click the <emphasis>Edit this setting</emphasis> button that
appears on hovering your mouse cursor over a setting. Once edit mode has
been entered, changes made to the fields from within the setting can be
saved by clicking the <emphasis>Save</emphasis> button on the right (or by
hitting the <emphasis>Enter</emphasis> key on your keyboard). If a setting
is currently edited by another administrator, it is not possible to get
access to the edit mode for that setting until the other administrator
finished their work. Editing can be cancelled by clicking the
<emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> button on the right or hitting the
<emphasis>Escape</emphasis> key on your keyboard. When editing is cancelled,
all changes made during the current editing session are discarded.
</para>

<para>
Clicking the setting name or the menu icon on the top right of each setting
will reveal a menu with some more options (e.g. enable/disable a setting,
reset a setting values to their defaults, copy a direct link to a setting or
add a setting to a list of favorites for quick access).
</para>

<para>
为了使更改生效，必须启动部署。 系统配置部署屏幕将显示要部署的设置清单。
单击每个设置左上方的箭头图标或外部<emphasis>更改概览</emphasis>框中的箭头图标，可以显示当前状态（即将部署）与之前（或
默认）状态的一对一比较情况。
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>系统配置部署</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-systemconfigurationdeployment.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
If you would like to save all the changes you made to your system
configuration (for example to quickly set up a new instance) you can use the
<emphasis>Export settings</emphasis> button, which will provide a
<filename>.yml</filename> file for downloading. To restore your own
settings, use <emphasis>Import settings</emphasis> and select the
<filename>.yml</filename> file you have created before.
</para>

<note>
<para>
For security reasons, the configuration settings for the database connection
cannot be changed in the graphical user interface of the system
configuration. These have to be set manually in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>.
</para>
</note>

</section>

</section>
