<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="configuration">
<title>Usanidi wa Mfumo</title>

<section id="directories-and-configfiles">
<title>Mafaili ua usanidi wa OTRS</title>

<para>
All OTRS configuration files are stored in the directory
<filename>Kernel</filename> and in its subdirectories. There is no need to
manually change any other file than <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>,
because the rest of the files will be changed when the system gets
upgraded. Just copy the configuration parameters from other files into
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> and change them as per your
needs. This file will never be touched during the upgrade process, so your
manual changes are safe.
</para>

<para>
The configuration can be rebuilt either manually by executing <literal>perl
bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Config::Rebuild</literal> or automatically by the
installer, package operations (install, upgrade, reinstall and uninstall),
etc. All <filename>.xml</filename> files located in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/XML/</filename> are parsed and their content
is transferred to the OTRS database. Most of the .xml files which are part
of this directory by default belong to OTRS Free, but OTRS Free Features
such as FAQ or Survey (or any other OTRS extension) will add their own
configuration files to this directory aswell.
</para>

<para>
To apply any sort of changes to the configuration, it is necessary to deploy
them. The deployment process will extract all settings and the according
values from the OTRS database, convert them to a format that OTRS can
understand naturally and put them into
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename>.
</para>

<para>
If the OTRS web interface is accessed, the settings contained in the files
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename>,
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZACL.pm</filename> (if existing),
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZProcessManagement.pm</filename> (if
existing) and any other custom .pm file will be evaluated
alphabetically. These files are used by the graphical user interface for
caching purposes and should never be changed manually. Lastly, the file
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> that contains your individual settings
and manually changed configuration parameters will be parsed. Reading the
configuration files in this order makes sure that your specific
configuration settings are considered correctly by the system.
</para>

</section>

<section id="sysconfig">
<title>Configuring the System Through the Web Interface</title>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Kiolesura michoro cha usanidi wa mfumo</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-systemconfiguration.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
OTRS Free currently brings more than 1700 configuration settings, and there
are different ways to quickly access a specific one. With the full text
search, all configuration settings can be scanned for one or more
keywords. The full text search not only searches through the names of the
configuration settings, but also the descriptions and values. This allows an
element to be found easily even if its name is unknown.
</para>

<para>
Furthermore, each configuration setting is classified by a category and a
navigation group. Navigation groups are individual elements in the main
navigation tree. By selecting one of these navigation entries, all settings
assigned to the selected group will be shown. As long as no extensions are
installed, the category selection is automatically hidden, but as soon as a
package is installed which brings its own configuration settings (such as
FAQ or Survey), the category selection will be revealed. Selecting a
category makes the main navigation tree show only the navigation groups
belonging to the selected category.
</para>

<para>
All configuration settings are shown as readonly by default. To edit a
setting, click the "Edit this setting" button that appears on hovering your
mouse cursor over a setting. Once edit mode has been entered, changes made
to the fields from within the setting can be saved by clicking the save
button on the right (or by hitting the enter key on your keyboard). If a
setting is currently edited by another administrator, it is not possible to
get access to the edit mode for that setting until the other administrator
finished their work. Editing can be cancelled by clicking the cancel button
on the right or hitting the "Escape" key on your keyboard. When editing is
cancelled, all changes made during the current editing session are
discarded.
</para>

<para>
Clicking the setting name or the menu icon on the the top right of each
setting will reveal a menu with some more options (e.g. enable/disabled a
setting, reset a settings values to their defaults, copy a direct link to a
setting or add a setting to a list of favorites for quick access).
</para>

<para>
To bring changes into effect, a deployment has to be started. The system
configuration deployment screen shows a list of the settings which are to be
deployed. Clicking the arrow icon on the top left of each setting or in the
outer "Changes Overview" box will show a one to one comparison between the
settings current state (which is about to be deployed) and the previous (or
default) state.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>System configuration deployment</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-systemconfigurationdeployment.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
If you would like to save all the changes you made to your systems
configuration (for example to quickly set up a new instance) you can use the
"Export settings" button, which will provide a .yml file for downloading. To
restore your own settings, use "Import settings" and select the .yml file
you have created before.
</para>

<note>
<para>
For security reasons, the configuration settings for the database connection
cannot be changed in the graphical user interface of the system
connfiguration. These have to be set manually in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>.
</para>
</note>

</section>

</section>
