<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="dynamicfield-contact-with-data">
    <title>The Dynamic Field <emphasis>Contact with Data</emphasis></title>

    <para>
        This feature allows to add contacts with data to tickets.
    </para>

    <section>
        <title>描述</title>
        <section>
            <title>Definition of Data Sources</title>
            <para>
                The data sources for this feature reside on the Dynamic Fields of the new
<emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis> type, this mean that each dynamic
field of this type is a new data source. The name of the dynamic field will
become the name of the data source, as they are both the same.
            </para>
            <para>
                For each data source (dynamic field) a list of contact attributes can be
defined (each attribute can contain only one text based value). The contact
attributes can be set as mandatory and searchable if needed. The sort order
of the attributes can be also defined.
            </para>
            <para>
                Contact attributes for each data source could contain any information about
the contact as needed, such as different addresses, telephone, birthday,
anniversaries, favorite food, hobbies, etc.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The attributes <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are
always mandatory and they are not automatically added, so for each new data
source these attributes must be added manually.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Within the data source definition (or dynamic field configuration) they must
be represented by the keys <literal>Name</literal> and
<literal>ValidID</literal> respectively while the values could be
<emphasis>Name</emphasis> and <emphasis>Validity</emphasis> for example.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Contact Management</title>
            <para>
                After having at least one data source (Contact with data Dynamic Field)
defined, contacts information can be added to the source to populate it.
            </para>
            <para>
                Apart from the <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal>, each
data source could contain different contact information as defined by the
data source (e.g. a data source could have an E-mail field while another
could contain Telephone and/or Mobile fields).
            </para>
            <para>
                The management (adding or updating) contact for the data sources is done by
an special screen that can be called from the Ticket menu (<emphasis>Edit
contacts with data</emphasis>) in the main navigation bar.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding Contacts to Tickets</title>
            <para>
                For each configured contact with data dynamic field, a contact created
specifically for this dynamic field (or data source) can be chosen from any
ticket create or ticket action screen where the dynamic filed has been
previously configured.
            </para>
            <para>
                The contact attributes will be shown in the ticket zoom screen.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Usage of Contacts in Search and Statistics</title>
            <para>
                Tickets can be found in search and statistics via the required attribute
<literal>Name</literal>.
            </para>
            <para>
                The <literal>Name</literal> can also be returned as a field value.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>配置</title>

        <variablelist>
            <title>系统配置</title>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>AdminContactWithData::RunInitialWildcardSearch</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Navigation: <literal>Frontend::Admin::View::ContactWithData</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Defines if a search with placeholder should be executed when initially
calling the contact management.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>Frontend::Module###AdminContactWithData</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Navigation: <literal>Frontend::Admin::ModuleRegistration</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Allows to distribute contact and contact detail management permissions via
group definition.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

    </section>

    <section>
        <title>用法</title>
        <para>
            An exemplary usage of contacts with data is as follows:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Create a new dynamic field of type <emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the possible contact attributes (possible
values). <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are required
for any Contact with data Dynamic Field.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>Name</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>Name</literal>, Value:
<emphasis>Name</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>ValidID</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>ValidID</literal>,
Value: <emphasis>Validity</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add any other attribute such as <literal>Telephone</literal> attribute (Key:
<literal>Telephone</literal>, Value: <emphasis>Phone</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of mandatory attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the attribute key order list comma separated as:
<literal>Name,Telephone,ValidID</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of searchable attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> is not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Populate the data source by adding at least one contact in the newly created
data source by using <emphasis>Tickets → Edit contacts with data</emphasis>
screen from the main navigation bar.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the new dynamic field to the screen's configuration where it should be
shown. For example in <emphasis>New Phone Ticket</emphasis> screen by
updating the system configuration setting:
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketPhone###DynamicField</literal> and do
the same for
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketZoom###DynamicField</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Go to <emphasis>New phone ticket</emphasis> screen, and notice that the new
field is there. Add all ticket needed information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Select an existing contact using autocomplete and choosing a contact.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The assigned contact and its attributes will be shown in the ticket zoom
screen.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    It is possible to update the attributes of the contact by clicking the
<emphasis>Edit contact data</emphasis> button that appears in the right side
of the title of the contact data box (if the current user is a member of the
groups defined in system configuration setting
<literal>Frontend::Module###AdminDynamicFieldContactWithData</literal>).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    If is necessary to change the contact for this ticket, it can be done via
any other ticket action where the dynamic field is configured for display.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
</section>
