<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="sms-communication-channel">
    <title>SMS Communication Channel</title>
    <section>
        <title>描述</title>
        <para>
            This feature brings another communication channel to your OTRS instance: SMS
(Short Message Service). It allows you to leverage SMS cloud service to send
out messages and store them as article in tickets.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="sms-cloud-service-activate">
        <title>Activating SMS Cloud Service</title>
        <para>
            Before taking advantage of SMS cloud service, you must first activate it. To
do so, please visit the <emphasis>Cloud Services</emphasis> screen in Admin
interface, and click on SMS entry in table.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Cloud Services Screen in Admin Interface</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-cloud-service.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                In order to use SMS cloud service, you have to buy an SMS unit
package. Please get in touch with sales@otrs.com on this matter. Once you've
bought a package, you will be able to look up your current contingent of
remaining SMS units in the sidebar of the cloud service configuration
screen.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            To activate SMS cloud service, make sure to accept the Data Protection
agreement by selecting the checkbox.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Activating SMS Cloud Service</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-cloud-service-config.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            On this screen, you can also set up some additional parameters of the SMS
cloud service, e.g. the sender string which should be used for the SMS text
messages or the agent/customer preference field name which should be used to
take the mobile phone number from.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                If you change value for the customer preference field, make sure to update
the configuration options of the address book in the system configuration to
reflect this change:
            </para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><literal>CustomerUser::Frontend::AgentCustomerUserAddressBook###SearchParameters###SMS</literal></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><literal>CustomerUser::Frontend::AgentCustomerUserAddressBook###DefaultFields###SMS</literal></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><literal>CustomerUser::Frontend::AgentCustomerUserAddressBook###ShowColumns###SMS</literal></para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>
                This will make sure your configuration stays in sync and phone numbers can
be found/copied from correct fields.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Allowed role members</emphasis> is an optional white list of agent
roles whose members will be able to receive SMS notifications. If undefined,
all agents will have a possibility of receiving SMS notifications.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Perform URL shortening</emphasis> checkbox controls the feature of
shortening links in SMS texts. If enabled, any link submitted as part of SMS
text will be shortened by using OTRS cloud URL shortening service. Links
will be shortened only if their length is larger than resulting shortened
URL, in order to keep SMS costs down.
        </para>
        <para>
            By adding specific phone numbers to the <emphasis>Phone black
list</emphasis>, you can make sure these numbers will never receive any SMS
text via cloud service (whether it's a notification or an article). Make
sure to input phone numbers in international format, complete with plus sign
(+) and country code, without any spaces.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuring SMS Templates</title>
        <para>
            In order to benefit from SMS templates, you must first configure them for
specific screens and assign them to correct queues. You can find
<emphasis>SMS template management</emphasis> screen in the Admin interface.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Manage SMS Templates</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-template-overview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            SMS templates behave similar to regular email templates. You define them
first, and then assign to queues with which you would like to use them.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Template Type</emphasis> field determines for which screen the
template will be visible:
        </para>
        <para>
            <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>Answer</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Template will be visible for <emphasis>Reply via SMS article</emphasis>
action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>Create</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Template will be visible in <emphasis>New SMS ticket</emphasis> screen.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>SMSOutbound</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Template will be visible in <emphasis>SMS Outbound</emphasis> screen.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                <literal>Create</literal> type templates only supports these smart tags:
<literal>&lt;OTRS_CURRENT_*&gt;</literal> and
<literal>&lt;OTRS_CONFIG_*&gt;</literal>.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            When you define an SMS template, don't forget to add them to queues. You can
do this by following link in the sidebar or via <emphasis>SMS Templates ↔
Queues</emphasis> link in the admin interface.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Manage SMS Templates</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-template-queue-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Creating SMS Tickets</title>
        <para>
            To create a ticket with SMS article as a first one, please go to the
<emphasis>New SMS ticket</emphasis> screen accessible via
<emphasis>Tickets</emphasis> menu on the main tool-bar.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>New SMS Ticket Screen</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-ticket-create.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            This screen behaves similar to new email and phone screens, with some
notable exceptions. Instead of email addresses,
<emphasis>Recipients</emphasis> field accepts only phone numbers in
international format, complete with plus sign (+) and country code. You can
also search for customer users via this field, provided they have a valid
phone number stored in preference field which is configured in cloud service
configuration screen.
        </para>
        <para>
            You may also utilize address book by clicking on small icon next to the
recipients field. Search form will allow you to find customer user you are
looking for, and add their phone number to the list of recipients.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Ticket Title</emphasis> field will not be included in SMS and is
for internal use only. Customer will receive message based exclusively on
the contents of the <emphasis>Text</emphasis> field.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            If you have configured SMS templates of type <literal>Create</literal>, and
you have them assigned to currently chosen <emphasis>Queue</emphasis>, you
will have the option of populating the <emphasis>Text</emphasis> field with
pre-configured message.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Flash message</emphasis> checkbox controls if message will be
showed directly on the device without user interaction and not stored
automatically.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Support for flash messages (also known as <emphasis>Class 0</emphasis>
messages) may vary by device and provider. OTRS cannot guarantee if this
flag will be honored by service provider or supported by receiving device.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            By clicking <emphasis>Send SMS</emphasis> button, ticket will be created
with an SMS article, provided SMS cloud service accepted the message. If any
errors were encountered, you will be notified, and ticket will not be
created.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Creating SMS Articles</title>
        <para>
            To add an SMS to an existing ticket, you can use <emphasis>SMS
Outbound</emphasis> action on the main ticket tool-bar
(<emphasis>Communication</emphasis> section).
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>New SMS Ticket Screen</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-ticket-outbound.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            If you already have an article, you can also use <emphasis>Reply via
SMS</emphasis> action on the article tool-bar. Simply select the article in
question, and either click on the button, or choose name of the template (if
you have it configured for this screen).
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>New SMS Ticket Screen</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-reply.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            If customer user has defined phone number, it will be automatically inserted
in the recipients list. It doesn't matter if article was created in a
different communication channel (e.g. Email), it should be correctly
recognized and substituted with valid phone number.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Please note that SMS character counter might not be reflecting the final
message size. This is especially true if message text contains OTRS tags or
links and URL shorting feature is turned on. Since text replacement will
occur during sending of the message, there is no way to guarantee final
size, and counter should be taken only for informative purposes.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Displaying SMS Articles</title>
        <para>
            SMS articles can be displayed as they were sent out right in the ticket zoom
screen. Their contents will reflect the final state of the message as queued
by the SMS cloud service for sending (with all tags replaced and links
shortened).
        </para>
        <para>
            Recipients of an SMS article are listed inside the
<emphasis>Recipients</emphasis> field. They can be shown in two formats:
just phone numbers or phone numbers with name of corresponding customer
users. In addition to this field, <emphasis>Transaction Numbers</emphasis>
will contain a reference message ID mapped to the recipients phone
number. These numbers can be used for debugging purposes, since they can be
connected to specific messages handled by the cloud service.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>SMS Article Display</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-ticket-zoom.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            In addition to the article header field, transaction numbers can also be
found in <emphasis>Ticket History</emphasis> screen. This screen will
contain an entry for every message sent out via SMS cloud service, with
corresponding transaction and phone number in it.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>SMS Ticket History Entries</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/sms-communication-channel/sms-ticket-history.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
