<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="notification-methods">
    <title>Notification Methods</title>

    <section>
        <title>Описание</title>
        <para>
            Ticket and appointment calendar notifications can be sent to their
recipients using one or multiple methods.  Every notification can activate
its preferred method to be sent, and by default all notifications are sent
using the email method, where the information about the notification is
embedded into an email for the recipient.
        </para>
        <para>
            However, OTRS offers more transportation methods to send the notifications,
please take a look below for their configuration and usage.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="notification-methods-web-view">
        <title>Notification Web View</title>
        <para>
            This transportation method is only intended for agents and instead of
actually sending the notifications in any form, they are stored in the
system database in order to be displayed in an special screen in the agent
interface.
        </para>
        <section id="notification-methods-web-view-setup-and-use">
            <title>Setting up and Using the Notification Web View</title>
            <para>
                To set up the notification web view for agents, it's just as simple as
clicking on its activation check-box for every notification.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Enabling the Notification Web View</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/notification-web-view.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Once you've enabled the notification web view for a certain notification,
agents will see a new icon on top of their screen in OTRS (within the
tool-bar) every time a new notification arrives.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Notification Web View Icon on the Tool-bar</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/notification-web-view-new.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Clicking this icon, agents will get an overview of all of their
notifications where they can read and dismiss them.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Notification Web View Overview</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/notification-web-view-overview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Notification Web View Detail</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/notification-web-view-detail.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="notification-methods-sms">
        <title>SMS Notifications</title>

        <para>
            SMS notification is technically a notification method besides the existing
email method and can be activated for each notification
(e.g. <emphasis>Ticket new note notification</emphasis> or <emphasis>Ticket
create notification</emphasis>) on the <emphasis>Notification
Event</emphasis> screen in the Admin interface.
        </para>

        <section id="notification-settingup-sms">
            <title>Setting up SMS Notifications</title>
            <para>
                Before taking advantage of SMS notification transport method, you must first
activate the SMS cloud service.
            </para>
            <para>
                In order to use SMS as a way of notification for users and customers, you
have to buy an SMS unit package.  Please get in touch with sales@otrs.com on
this matter. Once you've bought a package, you will be able to look up your
current contingent of remaining SMS units on the admin screen for the SMS
cloud service.
            </para>
            <para>
                To make SMS available for notifications, you have to enable it for the
notification of your choice in <emphasis>Ticket Notification</emphasis> or
<emphasis>Appointment Notification</emphasis> screen in the Admin
interface. Besides the existing Email notification method, you can enable
SMS notifications by enabling the checkbox as to be seen in the screenshot
below.
            </para>
            <para>
                Please be careful using the <emphasis>Send by default</emphasis> checkbox on
SMS notifications. Enabling this checkbox will cause this notification to be
sent by SMS to all agents with a phone number stored in the configured
field. This could cause a high usage of your available SMS units!
            </para>
            <para>
                On this screen, you can also add more generic phone numbers (e.g. for
archiving purposes) which will receive all of the relevant notifications
(besides the addressed agents). Please note that all of these recipients
will be treated as customers (regarding article creation).
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Enabling SMS Notifications</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/sms-notification-transport.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                If you configured a notification to be visible in the agent preferences,
agents will now be able to enable/disable SMS notifications manually on
their own for this notification.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Agent Preferences SMS Notification Settings</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/sms-notification-agent-preferences.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                SMS notification text will be constructed on fly by combining both
<emphasis>Subject</emphasis> and <emphasis>Text</emphasis> fields of the
corresponding language. You can of course use supported OTRS tags in these
fields, and additionally URLs can be shortened by activating URL shortening
option in cloud service configuration.
            </para>
            <figure>
                <title>SMS Notification Text Fields</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/notification-methods/sms-notification-text.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
