<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="updating">
    <title>Updating OTRS</title>

    <note>
        <para>
            Настоятельно рекомендуем выполнить сначала тестовое обновление в отдельной
тестовой среде.
        </para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Updating from an earlier version of OTRS 7</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    You can update directly from any previous to the latest available patch
level release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Updating from OTRS 6</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    You can update from any OTRS 6 patch level to the latest available OTRS 7
patch level release.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Updating from OTRS 5 or earlier</term>
            <listitem>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        You cannot update from OTRS 5 or earlier directly to OTRS 7.  Full updates
to all available minor versions have to be made sequentially instead.  For
example, if you come from OTRS 4.0, you first have to perform a full update
to OTRS 5, then to 6 and finally to OTRS 7.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 1: Stop all relevant services and the OTRS Daemon</title>

        <para>
        Please make sure there are no more running services or cron jobs that try to
access OTRS.  This will depend on your service configuration, here is an
example:
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
root> /etc/init.d/cron stop
root> /etc/init.d/postfix stop
root> /etc/init.d/apache stop
            ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <para>
        Stop OTRS cron jobs and the daemon (in this order):
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/Cron.sh stop
otrs> bin/otrs.Daemon.pl stop
            ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <para>
            If you perform a patch level update of OTRS 7, you need to also stop the
built-in OTRS web server: <screen>
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/otrs.WebServer.pl --stop
            </screen>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 2: Backup files and database</title>

        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/WebApp.conf</filename> (only in case of a patch level
update of OTRS 7, and only if the file was modified)</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para><filename>var/*</filename></para></listitem>
                <listitem><para>а также базы данных</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <warning>
            <para>Don't proceed without a complete backup of your system.</para>
        </warning>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
    <title>Step 3: Install the new release</title>

        <note>
            <para>
                With OTRS 7 RPMs are no longer provided. RPM based installations need to
switch by uninstalling the RPM (this will not drop your database) and using
the source archives instead.
            </para>
        </note>

        <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd /opt
root> mv otrs otrs-old
root> tar -xzf otrs-x.x.x.tar.gz
root> mv otrs-x.x.x otrs
        ]]></screen>

        <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Восстановить старые конфигурационные файлы</title>

            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename></para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para><filename>Kernel/WebApp.conf</filename> (only in case of a patch level
update of OTRS 7, and only if the file was modified)</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Восстановить данные статьи</title>

            <para>
                If you configured OTRS to store article data in the file system you have to
restore the <filename>article</filename> folder to
<filename>/opt/otrs/var/</filename> or the folder specified in the System
Configuration.
            </para>
        </section>


        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Restore already installed default statistics</title>

            <para>
                If you have additional packages with default statistics you have to restore
the stats xml files with the suffix <filename>*.installed</filename> to
<filename>/opt/otrs/var/stats</filename>.
            </para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd OTRS-BACKUP/var/stats
root> cp *.installed /opt/otrs/var/stats
            ]]></screen>
        </section>

        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Установка прав доступа к файлам.</title>

            <para>
                Please execute the following command as root user to set the file and
directory permissions for OTRS.  It will try to detect the correct user and
group settings needed for your setup.
            </para>

            <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
root> cd /opt/otrs/
root> bin/otrs.SetPermissions.pl
            ]]></screen>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Install Required Programs and Perl Modules</title>
            <para>
                Please refer to the <link linkend="installation-of-perl-modules">section in
the installation guide</link> that explains how to verify external
dependencies such as Perl modules and Node.js.
            </para>
            <para>
                In addition to that, OTRS 7 also requires an active cluster of Elasticsearch
6.0 or higher. Please refer to the <link
linkend="installation-setup-elasticsearch-cluster">Setup Elasticsearch
Cluster</link> section in the installation guide.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 4: Run the migration script</title>

        <note>
            <para>
                If you have any custom Perl or XML configuration files in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename>, these need to be <ulink
url="http://doc.otrs.com/doc/manual/developer/6.0/en/html/package-porting.html#packge-porting-5-to-6-configuration-files">converted
to the new formats supported by OTRS 7</ulink> before running the migration
script.
            </para>
        </note>

        <para>
            The migration script will perform many checks on your system and give you
advice on how to install missing Perl modules etc., if that is required. If
all checks succeeded, the necessary migration steps will be
performed. Please also run this script in case of patch level updates.
        </para>

        <para>
            Run the migration script (as user <literal>otrs</literal>, NOT as
<literal>root</literal>):
        </para>

        <para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> scripts/DBUpdate-to-7.pl
        ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <warning>
            <para>
                Do not continue the upgrading process if this script did not work properly
for you.  Otherwise malfunction or data loss may occur.
            </para>
        </warning>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 5: Update installed packages</title>
        <note>
            <para>
                Packages for OTRS 6 are not compatible with OTRS 7 and have to be updated.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            You can use the command below to update all installed packages.  This works
for all packages that are available from online repositories.  You can
update other packages later via the package manager (this requires a running
OTRS Daemon).
        </para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/otrs.Console.pl Admin::Package::UpgradeAll
        ]]></screen>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 6: Restart your services</title>

        <para>
            OTRS 7 comes with an own built-in web server that is used behind apache as a
reverse proxy (or any other reverse proxy server). For major updates from
OTRS 6, the apache configuration must be updated with the new version in
<filename>/opt/otrs/scripts/apache2-httpd.include.conf</filename>, if it was
copied and not just linked. Please also note that while mod_perl is no
longer needed, other Apache modules are required now:
<literal>proxy_module</literal>, <literal>proxy_http_module</literal> and
<literal>proxy_wstunnel_module</literal>.
        </para>

        <para>
            After that, the services can be restarted.  This will depend on your service
configuration, here is an example:
        </para>

        <para>
        <screen><![CDATA[
root> /etc/init.d/apache start
root> /etc/init.d/postfix start
root> /etc/init.d/cron start
        ]]></screen>
        </para>

        <note>
            <para>
                The OTRS Daemon is required for correct operation of OTRS such as sending
emails.  Please activate it as described in the next step.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Step 7: Start the OTRS Daemon, web server and cron job</title>

        <para>
            The OTRS Daemon is responsible for handling any asynchronous and recurring
tasks in OTRS.  The daemon and its keepalive cron job must be started as the
<literal>otrs</literal> user.  The built-in OTRS web server process handles
the web requests handed over from Apache.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
otrs> cd /opt/otrs/
otrs> bin/otrs.Daemon.pl start
otrs> bin/Cron.sh start
otrs> bin/otrs.WebServer.pl
            ]]></screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Now you can log into your system.
        </para>
    </section>

</section>
