<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="video-calls">
    <title>Video and Audio Calls</title>

    <section>
        <title>Maelezo</title>
        <para>
            The video and audio calls feature provides real-time calls between two users
right from the comfort of the OTRS frontend. The calls will be provided over
a direct peer-to-peer connection established between two users, where
possible. This feature depends heavily on the chat, which must be active for
video and audio calls to be possible.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Video and audio calls are based on a quite young technology called
WebRTC. The implementation of WebRTC APIs in modern browsers is an ongoing
effort. Currently, OTRS video and audio calls are supported only in the
latest versions of Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome (for Chrome a <link
linkend="chrome-ssl-required">HTTPS Enabled Web Server</link> is required).
            </para>
            <para>
                To use this feature correctly the OTRS system must have a valid contract
with the OTRS group.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Usanidi</title>
        <para>
            The following system configuration options are relevant for this feature.
        </para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>ChatEngine::Active</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                    Controls whether or not the video and audio calling feature is
enabled. Please note that the same switch will control <link
linkend="chat">the chat</link> feature too.
                </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>ChatEngine::PermissionGroup::VideoChatAgents</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                <para>
                    Defines the group for the video and audio calling features. Only agents with
permission in this group will be able to make video and audio calls.
                </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Setup</title>
        <para>
            In order to be able to start video and audio calls, you need to setup
certain things in your OTRS instance.
        </para>
        <section>
            <title>Chat Setup</title>
            <para>
                You need a working chat setup in your system. Make sure to carefully read
the <link linkend="chat-setup-availability">Setup</link> section of the chat
feature.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section id="chrome-ssl-required">
            <title>HTTPS Enabled Web Server</title>
            <para>
                Currently, Google Chrome will allow access to a user's media streams only to
web applications served over the HTTPS protocol (SSL) with valid signed
certificates. Make sure you have set the <emphasis
role="bold">HttpType</emphasis> config option to <emphasis>https</emphasis>,
too. Setting up a web server to be accessible via HTTPS is outside of the
scope of this manual.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Availability for calls</title>
            <para>
                To be available for video and audio calls, you have to make sure you are
available for chats too. Please refer to the instructions in <link
linkend="chat-setup-availability">Agents: Set up Availability</link> for
more information.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>On-line User Dashboard Widget</title>
            <para>
                For a convenient way to start the calls, please activate the
<emphasis>On-line</emphasis> widget on the Dashboard.
            </para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Go to the Dashboard and expand the <emphasis>Settings</emphasis> widget.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Check the <emphasis>On-line</emphasis> widget and make sure to click
<emphasis>Save settings</emphasis>.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Setting up the On-line widget on Dashboard</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/dashboard-settings-online-widget.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Usage</title>
        <section>
            <title>Chat Requirement</title>
            <para>
                Video and audio calls are tied to existing chats. As an agent, you will be
able to initiate calls inside and outside of chats. Customer users will be
able to initiate calls only from an active chat.
            </para>
            <para>
                If a chat does not yet exist, it will be created when the call is
initiated. In these "ad-hoc" chats, the chat parties are joined
automatically. When a call is terminated, these chats will remain active
until they are closed manually.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Making the Video Calls</title>
            <para>
                To make a call inside of an active chat, simply click on the small video
camera button in the chat header.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Making a call inside the chat</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-chat-video-buttons.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                A popup window will open, and depending on your browser, you will be asked
to share your video and audio streams. On systems with several cameras and
microphones, you will be able to choose exactly the one you would like to
use from the drop down list.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Media Permission Request</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/media-permission-request.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Once you confirm your choice, an invitation will be sent to the other party
asking them to join. You will be notified of the progress via a message in
the center of the screen.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Waiting for the other party</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-waiting-other-party.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Please just wait a little while until the connection is established. Then
you will be able to see and hear the other party.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Established Connection</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-established-connection.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                To control your streams, simply toggle the mute buttons on the left side.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Mute Buttons</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-mute-buttons.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                To leave a call, simply click on the big red <emphasis>Close</emphasis>
button. The other party will be notified.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Audio Calls</title>
            <para>
                The only difference between video and audio calls is that audio calls will
mute your video stream initially (which you will be able to turn on later in
the call). The video stream will be muted for both parties by default, but
they will be able to control it.
            </para>
            <para>
                If the other party has muted their video stream, instead of the video you
will see a large microphone icon in the center, along with their name. The
icon will reflect the state of their audio stream, and if they mute it too,
it will be crossed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Audio Only</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-audio-only.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Call Invitations</title>
            <para>
                If you have made yourself available for chats (either internal or external),
video and audio call invitations are received automatically by one of the
active tabs in the same user session. When you receive an invitation, a
modal dialog will be displayed on your screen, allowing you to accept or
decline the invitation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Call Invitation</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-invitation-dialog.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Your browser may also present you a notification with sound. This heavily
depends on the used browser and operating system settings, and if permission
has been granted to OTRS to trigger such notifications. A permission request
will be displayed the first time you change your chat availability.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Notification Permission Request</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-notification-permission-request.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Other ways to start Video and Audio Calls</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Agent to Agent</emphasis></para>
                    <para>
                        To start a video or audio call with another agent, with whom you do not have
an active chat, you can use the <emphasis>On-line</emphasis> widget on the
dashboard.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Online widget on the Dashboard</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/dashboard-online-widget-agents.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Agents who are able to receive calls will have a video camera and microphone
icon next to their name which you can click on. Once clicked, a popup window
will open, asking you to share your media streams. The connection will be
established afterwards.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Calling other agents is possible also via Owner and Responsible fields in
ticket zoom. In this case, check will also be done to make sure the other
agent is available, before allowing the call to be initiated.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Calling other agents from Ticket Zoom</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-ticket-zoom-owner.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Agent to Customer</emphasis></para>
                    <para>
                        To start a video or audio call with a customer, with whom you do not have an
active chat, you can use the customer user widget in the Customer
Information Center when viewing a certain customer. Available customers will
have call icons next to their name which you can click on. Once clicked, a
popup window will open asking you to share your media streams. The
connection will be established afterwards.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Making a call from Customer Information Center</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-cic.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Another possibility is to make a call directly from the ticket zoom. If the
customer user who is assigned to this ticket is currently on-line, you'll be
able to use call buttons next to their user name in customer information box
in right sidebar.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Making a call from Ticket Zoom</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/agent-video-ticket-zoom-customer.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Customer to Agent</emphasis></para>
                    <para>
                        Customer users will be able to initiate calls from an active chat only. To
do this, customers can use the video and audio call links in the header of
an active chat to initiate calls.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Starting a Video Call from Customer interface</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/features/video-calls/customer-video-call.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        When customers click on a link, they will be asked for permission to their
media streams, similar to agents. An invitation will be sent and the
connection will be established if the agent on the other side accepts the
request.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        The difference between video and audio calls in the customer interface
compared to the agent interface is minimal. Customers will see their calls
inside the same window as the chat. Only one additional button is provided:
Fullscreen. It will resize the video to the extent of the browser
window. Other than that, everything as in the agent interface applies.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis>Public to Agent</emphasis></para>
                    <para>
                        Users of the public interface are not able to make audio and video calls.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Connection</title>
        <para>
            In the best case scenario, video and audio calls will be streamed over a
direct peer-to-peer connection between users' browsers. The requirement is
that the user's network allows connection over a high port that WebRTC uses,
and can advertise this to the other party. To this end, there are several
mechanisms in place to aid in connecting.
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis>STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT)</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    STUN is a standardized set of methods and a network protocol to allow an end
host to discover its public IP address if it is located behind a NAT. OTRS
provides a cloud service with STUN to all systems with a valid contract, and
this data is shared with the other party to allow the connection to be
established.
                </para>
                <para>
                    In case of a connection via STUN, only the connection data is stored on the
OTRS servers, the connection itself is still directly between two users.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis>TURN (Traversal Using Relays around NAT) over UDP</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    TURN is a protocol that assists in traversal of network address translators
or firewalls for multimedia applications. OTRS also provides TURN cloud
service which can help clients on networks masqueraded by symmetric NAT
devices and it supports the connection of a user behind a NAT.
                </para>
                <para>
                    In case of a connection established via TURN server, media streams will be
routed through the server (like a proxy). In this situation, all packets are
securely transmitted to the other side. The access to the TURN server is
encrypted and secured by often changed credentials, which are provided
automatically.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis>TURN over TCP</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    In case all UDP traffic is blocked between two users, the TURN server over
TCP is a last resort for a successful connection. While TCP is not an ideal
protocol for transmitting media packets, it's a last resort in an effort to
connect two users and share their streams.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Same as with TURN over UDP, media streams will be routed through the server
and sent to the other side. The infrastructure for all STUN and TURN
services is highly scalable based on demand and can even be provided for
different geographic locations, in order to provide the best possible
throughput.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

</section>
